#### Contact

r\_jonesrn@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-raquel-biati-dnp-msn-rn-83657b63 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Nursing

Healthcare

Hospitals

#### Certifications

ACLS

**PALS** 

**TNCC** 

**BLS** 

#### Honors-Awards

Good Samaritan Foundation Award BRONZE MEDALIST in the Nursing Administration & Leadership Category.

Harris Health Hero- June 2015

# Dr.Raquel Biati, DNP, MSN, RN

Chief Executive Officer at Houston

Katy, Texas

# Summary

Respected leader, able to build highly motivated teams focused on achieving healthcare quality goals.

Exhibits inquisitiveness and keeps up-to-date with changes in the industry through continuing professional development and research of evidence based practice.

Highly skilled career professional with over 10 years of nursing experience in hospital and primary care environments.

Demonstrates willingness to reconsider and revise views where honest reflection suggests that change is warranted.

Computer skilled, with experience in documenting and generating reports.

Possesses the ability to multitask in a fast-paced environment, while maintaining an emphasis on quality.

Proficient in the development of documentation/record maintenance/ electronic medical recording procedures that ensure accuracy and patient confidentiality.

Competent deliverer of nursing care in major and minor emergent procedures performed in hospital environment.

# Experience

Houston

2 years 8 months

Chief Executive Officer
May 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Consulting Administrator
October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Responsible for ensuring the daily operations of the facility achieve all financial and clinical objectives, regulatory requirements, and the Organization's Mission. Responsible for the daily accounting including oversight over internal

controls, management of cash, and development/review of purchased services and contracts.

Responsible for developing and implementing the short and long-range operational and capital budget goals. Able to maintain excellent physician and partner relationships by employing strategies that encourage physician interest in growing volume and clinical opportunities.

Strong clinical background in nursing services and accreditation. Administrate over all Business Office functions in addition to Risk Management, Infection Control, Employee Health, Performance Improvement, Clinical Practice, Recruitment/Retention, Accreditation, Materials Management and the development and review of all Policies and Procedures.

HealthSouth
Chief Nursing Officer
April 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 7 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Responsible for the development and implementation of the plans for providing nursing care, treatment, and services including determination of the types and numbers of nursing personnel necessary to provide nursing care and the development of a patient focused, team oriented culture, working in conjunction with all other medical, clinical and therapeutic disciplines to ensure optimal service and superior outcomes.

- Reduced staff turnover from 24% to 12% by improving staff/patient ratios
- Improved staff morale resulting in increased staff retention rate and decreased contract staff utilization.
- Decreased fall rate by 60% within first year by developing L.A.M.P. program
- Increased Press Ganey patient satisfaction scores from 60% to 90%.
- Established "safety zone" for medication administration to decrease medication error.
- Significantly decreased Hospital Acquired Pressure Ulcers by establishing an in-house wound care team.
- Assisted with the implementation of ReACT to decrease acute care transfers.
- Facilitated a successful implementation of Electronic Medical Record (Cerner)

Executive Nurse Manager
January 2013 - April 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Responsible for 48 nursing staff, ancillary staff and clinic operations that serves over 4,000 patients a month in Triage, Urgent Episodic Clinic, Special Procedures, Family Practice, Pediatric, OB/GYN, Well Woman Clinic, Optometry, Behavioral Health, Psychiatry, Podiatry, Rheumatology, Nutrition, Diabetes Education and Medical Home Team.

- Manage variance report and operating budget, including FTEs and annual budget
- Manage billing and timely chart closure for Level of Service charges and facility charges
- Led the delivery of patient care and nursing services to achieve/exceed quality clinical standards and performance measures.
- Ensured and improved clinical practices, services and operations by designing and

implementing processes, procedures and methodologies to evaluate and improve

patient care

 Co-chaired and/or participated on several committees involved in development and implementation of organizational initiatives, protocols and processes to improve patient care and achieve financial goals

Kindred Healthcare
Nursing Manager ICU/MS/Tele
February 2012 - December 2012 (11 months)
Kindred Hospital- Sugarland

- •Oversee the hospital staff to ensure quality care and compliance with policies and mandated state regulations.
- •Provide professional guidance for nursing personnel, manage disciplinary issues, prepare administrative reports, review staffing and budgetary needs, and integrate Nursing Services functions with other hospital departments.
- •Participated in program development and training for nurse-recruitment activities and assist with continuing education programs.
- Directed staff in state accreditations, DADS and CARF.

Harris Health System-Ben Taub General Hospital 7 years

E.R. Nurse

April 2005 - March 2012 (7 years)

Ben Taub General Hospital

- •Administered critical IV medications such as Cardizem, Dopamine, Insulin, Nitroglycerin, and Adenosine
- •Assisted in the care of multiple traumas, cardiac arrests, stroke codes, sexual assaults and conscious sedations
- •Provided care to people across the lifespan with different conditions from infants, children, pregnant women, and the elderly
- •Acted as a team member/leader to perform ER tasks and served as preceptor for new graduates.
- •Assisted in the completion of rape kits and sexual assault examinations
- •Independently maintained safe and effective care to patients with different acuity levels in a time-restricted and demanding environment
- •Constantly communicated and collaborated with physicians and other healthcare professionals to ensure optimal care was given to patients in a timely manner
- •Leverage interpersonal communication strengths to establish rapport and build trust with patients and families

#### Dialysis Nurse

May 2008 - December 2011 (3 years 8 months)

Ben Taub General Hospital

Cared for patients with impaired kidney function undergoing hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis. Had an intricate knowledge of the mechanics of both types of dialysis; administered the dialysis from start to finish; discuss and explain concerns and answer relevant questions of the patient; and monitor and asses the patient's vital signs and reaction to treatment.

The Woman's Hospital of Texas
Registered Nurse

August 2005 - April 2006 (9 months)

Cared for women who are in labor, have pregnancy complications requiring hospitalizations of have recently delivered. Provide emotional support to patients and their families and develop an individualized plan of care for each mother. Educated patients women's health, newborn care and other related topics.

# Education

# Walden University

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Executive Leadership, Nursing Administration · (2016)

# Houston Community College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

# Texas Tech University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

# Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center

Master's Degree, Nursing Administration